내가 알고있는 권한이 있는 사람의 승인을 직접 듣지 않고는
I'm not going to annihilate
4.3 million Pakistanis
나는 4백3십만명의 파키스탄인들을 전멸시키지 않을것입니다
without hearing from someone
whose authority I recognize.
아군이 우리를 격침시키려고 했다구요?
Our own people
tried to sink us?
우리는 세인트 마리나 섬에 위치한
(Chaplin) We have commandeered
나토의 조기 경보 시설을
The NATO Early Warning Station
점령하고 있다
on the island of Sainte Marina.
이 섬 주위 200 마일에 대해
I am declaring
a 200-mile no-man's-land
비무장지대임을 선포한다
around this island.
경고했듯이
Test us, and we will all burn.
시험해보길 바란다, 다 태워버릴테니
You've been warned.
5일안에, 배우자와 가족들이 봉쇄구역을 지나
In five days, a ship will be
allowed through the blockade
이송될것이다
to transport your spouses
and family members.
(Cheers)
내일 모두가 DC 를 출발할것이라고 하는데요
They're saying everybody's
leaving from DC tomorrow.
그는 당신을 원해요
He wants you.
그럼 당신은 어떻게 할 계획인가요?
So what are you willing to do
about it?
당신에게 키스했었잖아요
(Christine) I kissed you.
남편을 봐야 겠어요
I need to see my husband
그래서 우리 결혼은 끝났다고 이야길 해야죠
so I can tell him
that it's over.
누군가 발사키를 가져갔어
Someone took my firing key.
우린 이제 더이상 핵무기를 발사할 능력이 없어
We now have no
nuclear launch capabilities.
그래서 내가 용의자인가요?
So I'm a suspect?
우린 이제 발사키 없이 버텨야 한다구요
We are defenseless
without our firing key.
당신네들이 부상당한 동료하나와 파키스탄을 빠져나오자마자
You guys bug out of Pakistan
with a wounded man
몇 시간뒤에 미국이 그곳으로 핵을 날렸는데
and a few hours later,
the US is nuking the joint?
이게 아무런 연관성이 없다는건가요?
How do you connect the dots?
왜 그들을 제거했지?
(James) Why did we kill
that guy?
명령이 바뀌었어
(Hopper) Orders changed.
누가? 누가 명령을 바꿨는데?
Who?
Who changed the orders?
항상 바뀌잖아
They change all the time.
오역/의역 난무하니 감안하고 감상하세요 피드백은 suhwan.2006@gmail.com 으로 by 지아아빠
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
(Static crackling) _
파키스탄, 카라치 USS 콜로라도와 랑데뷰 3시간전
We have liberated the package
짐은 풀려있으며, 안전하게 하나로 확보되었다
and are secure at safe one.
어두워진 이후에 줄루 랑데뷰 포인트로
Waiting on command,
then headed your way
이동할 것이며 명령을 대기중이다
to rendezvous zulu after dark.
(Radio chatter)
호프, 네가 나를 스타로 만들어줄거야
You're gonna make me
a star, Hop.
영상에 찍힌 네 모습은 우리 적군들에게는 아주 용기가 되겠다만
Recording you in action would
only encourage our enemies.
네 엉덩이를 타고 앉아있는 놈에게나 이야기해
Says the guy
sitting on his ass.
얼마나 더 걸려?
How much longer?
리포트 업로드가 거의 끝나가
I'm almost done
uploading the report.
파일이 엄청 크네
File's huge.
우리 핵과학자님들께서 분석해줄꺼야
Our nuclear nerd
must have been pretty thorough.
알았어
Roger that.
모두 조금만 기다리라고 이야기 할께
I'll tell 'em all
to hold tight.
이제 출발하나요?
So can we go now?
곧, 긴장되나?
Soon. Nervous?
(Chuckles)
파키스탄안에서 미국인들을 돕는것은
In Pakistan, helping Americans
한사람의 건강엔 조금은 모험적인 일이지
can be a little hazardous
to one's health.
그래... 얼마나 곧
So... how soon?
(Chuckles)
카말
Kamal...
게임 그만하고 이리와
_
우린 주변을 둘러보고 오지
We'll check the perimeter.
(Racks gun)
그가 옳아요, 당신도 알죠?
He's right, you know?
그들이 하는 일은 정말 위험해요
It is dangerous,
what they're doing.
글쎄요 제가 확신하는 건 우리가 일을 끝마치면 그들에게 훈장을 줄거라는것 정도죠
Well, I'll be sure to give 'em
a medal when we're done.
훈장과 기념리본..
(Chuckles) Yeah,
ribbons and medals
그것들은 단지 용기를 내기위한 덫에 불과한것들이죠
are merely the trappings
of valor.
이것은
This...
(Sets cards down)
이것은 현재 일어나고 있는 실제 순간이에요
This is the actual moment
that it happens.
당신은 당신의 무기가 있죠
You have your swords,
하지만 난 리포트가 있어요, 펜이죠
but I have my report, the pen.
그리고 오늘날 펜은 가장 강한 무기에요
And today the pen is mightier.
온 세상에 이걸 알린다면
It declares to the world
파키스탄에 유실된 핵무기가 없다는 것을
no stray nukes in Pakistan,
당신네 정부가 중재할 이유도 없고
no need for your government
to intervene.
전쟁도 없겠지
No war.
나와 술 한잔 같이 할텐가, 병사
You're going to have
a drink with me, soldier,
축하를 위해서
a celebration.
오늘날 전사가 평화를 만들었으니
Today the warrior
made the peace.
이봐 호프, 박사와 한잔 해
Hey, Hop,
drinks are on the doc.
(Banging)
(Banging continues)
(People speaking indistinctly)
이봐, 가족들을 실은 배는 언제 도착하지?
Hey. When does
the family boat arrive?
금방 오겠지, 정말 크리스마스 같군
Any time now.
It feels like Christmas.
여러분은 여기 갑판에 계신 가족들로부터
(Woman, British accent)
You can feel
사랑하는 가족을 곧 만난다는 것으로 인한 흥분과
the anticipation and excitement
from the families on this deck
설렘이 강해지는 것을 시간이 지날수록 느끼실 수 있습니다
to see their loved ones
growing stronger by the minute.
마커스 채플린함장이 선포한 세인트 마리나섬 주위
The last of our military escorts
peeled off
200마일 주변을 통과함으로써 우리 군의 호위는
as we crossed Marcus Chaplin's
famed 200-mile perimeter
더 이상 없어졌습니다
around the island
of Sainte Marina,
USS 콜로라도의 채플린함장과 함조원들이
where Chaplin and the crew
of the USS Colorado...
주시하고 있는것 같지만, 조만간 바로는 나타날것 같지 않습니다
Staring out there won't
make it show any sooner.
- 그들이 성공할 수 있을것 같지않아 - 나도 알아
(Huffs) I know.
그가 바로 저곳에 있다는게 믿기질 않아
It's hard to believe
that he's right there.
(Woman speaking indistinctly)
아직까지도 세계를 향한 크나큰 도발을 하고 있는 중입니다
...still a threat
to the world at large.
오늘 우리가 도착한 것이..
Today, the arrival of...
인도군의 프라나브 밧나가로프 장군이
(Man) General Pranav Bhatnagar
of the Indian Army
어젯밤 사전 경고없이 그의 부대를 카시미르로 진격했습니다
moved his battalion
without warning last night
into Kashmir,
60년 넘게 인도와 파키스탄 사이에서
a territory which has been
the main source of strife
이 지역은 영토 분쟁의 주요 중심이 되었던 곳으로
between India and Pakistan
for over 60 years.
파키스탄은 군사행동을..
With Pakistan's ability to...
가족들이 이송되고 있습니다
The families
have been transferred
'니미츠' 호의 평화 사절로써
from the "nimitz" to the envoy.
곧 도착할 것 같습니다
They'll be here soon.
많은 승조원들이 질문을 하고 있습니다A lot of the crewhave been asking
A lot of the crew
have been asking
이번 방문이 부부면회가 가능한지 말입니다, 함장님
if these will be
conjugal visits, sir.
그래, 당연히 그렇지
Yeah, I'm sure they are.
(Chuckles)
그들을 평평한 보트위에서 30분간
They'll, uh, have a half an hour
on the open water
아무도 없는 바다 위에서 내버려둔다면..
with a boat
that's mostly a flat-top,
상상에 맡기겠네
so let imagination reign.
(Laughs)
지라드양, 상태는 어때요?
(Chaplin) Ms. Girard,
what's her status?
30마일 바깥쪽에서 들어오고 있어요
Inbound, 30 miles out,
15노트 속도로 문제없이 항해하고 있네요
sailing smoothly at 15 knots.
이곳에 도착예정시간은..
Should be here in--
(Alarm blaring)
뭐가 잘못됬나요?
(Kendal) Something wrong?
잘 모르겠어요
I'm not sure.
오디오 파일형식인데..
It's an audio signature,
그런데 소나 배열로 부터 들어오고 있어요
but it's coming through
the sonar arrays.
여보세요? 이것은 샘 켄달에게 보내는 메시지입니다
(Kylie) Hello? Hello,
this message is for Sam Kendal.
여보세요?
Hello?
(Clears throat)
제가 샘 켄달입니다
This is Sam Kendal.
시간이 많이 없어요
I don't have much time.
정부 라디오 주파수를 불법으로 사용하고 있어요
We're illegally using
a government radio frequency.
제 이름은 카일리 싱클레어에요
My name is Kylie Sinclair.
제 회사가 페르수스 시스템을 당신네 잠수함에
My company built
the Perseus system
탑재했어요
on board your sub,
그리고 최근엔 당신 아내와 친구가 되었죠
and I've recently become
friends with your wife.
당신아내가 이렇게 이야기 했어요
She told me to remind you
of a guy
당신이 태평양 해변에서 거의 죽을 정도로 싸웠었는데
you almost got into a fight with
in Pacific Beach.
그때 얼굴빛이 거의 토스터 같았었다구 했다구요
You said his face looked like
a toaster.
좋아요, 듣고 있어요
Okay. I'm listening.
파키스탄 해변에서 네이비씰 요원 몇을 태운적있죠?
You picked up some Navy SEALs
off the coast of Pakistan,
- 맞나요? - 맞아요
- correct?
- That is correct.
우리에게 믿을만한 이유가 있어요
We have reason to believe
정부가 그 네이비씰의 임무를 덮기 위해서
that everything
the government has done
모든일을 조작하고 진행했다는 사실을 말이에요
has been to cover up
that mission.
그래서 아직 거기 있는 네이비씰의 헬멧 카메라의 기록이
So the helmet-cam footage
that your SEALs still have
어느 누구도 없는 진실을 밝힐 가장 좋은 희망이라는 것이에요
is the best hope any of us have
for exposing the truth.
헬멧카메라의 기록용 메모리카드를 찾아서
You need to get Christine
the memory card
크리스틴에게 전달해줘야 해요
from that helmet-cam footage.
죄송한데요, 메모리카드를 어디 있는지도 모르는데
I'm sorry. Even if I can
get the memory cards,
크리스틴에게 어떻게 전달한단 말이나요?
how am I supposed to
get them to her?
사절단 보트 승선인원을 최종 수정했어요The government madea last-minute addition
The government made
a last-minute addition
to the envoy boat.
크리스틴이 거기 있어요
Christine is on it.
미안한데요, 크리스틴이 보트에 탔다구요?
Sorry. What do you mean
Christine's on the boat?
샘, 너무 많은 일이 있다는거 알아요
I know it's a lot, Sam,
하지만 날 믿어야되요
but please trust me.
그 카드를 찾아서
You need to find that card
크리스틴에게 꼭 전달해야되요
and you need to get it
to Christine.
신호가 끊겼어요
(Man) We got disconnected.
(Static crackles)
당신 아내, 그녀가 보트에 있대요?
Your wife, she's on the boat?
에
Yeah.
몇시간이면 그녀가 여길 오겠네요
She'll be here in a few hours.
(Indistinct conversations)
좋지 않네요, 뜨거운 것밖에 없어요
It's not good, but it's hot.
(Indistinct conversations
continue)
날 쳐다보고 있어요
They look at me,
TV에 나왔던 미친여자라고 생각할 거에요
and all they see
is that crazy lady from TV
또는 그들의 남편과 자식을 인질로 잡고 있는
or the wife of the man
who's holding their sons
남자의 아내로 생각하든지요
and husbands hostage.
내가 알기로는 새로운 삶을 시작하려는
I see a courageous woman
용감한 여자인데요
on the verge of starting
a new life.
크리스틴 켄달
Christine Kendal.
저는 레나 카푸어에요
I'm Rena Kapur.
- CZN 런던의 리포터에요 - 제 의뢰인은 말할 게 아무것도 없습니다
- I'm a reporter for CZN in London.
- My client has nothing to say.
전 당신 남편과 마커스 채플린함장이 진실을
I believe your husband
and Marcus Chaplin
이야기 한다고 믿고 있고 저 말고 다른사람들도 그렇답니다
are telling the truth,
and I'm not the only one.
전 단지 그들로 부터 듣고 싶을 뿐이에요
I just want them to be heard.
여기요, 크리스틴 저리 가요
Come on, Christine, let's go.
저기에 그들이 믿는 것을 지키고자 하는 이들이 있어요
There are people out there who
believe in what they stand for.
크리스틴!
Christine!
저 혼자 리포터는 감당할 수 있어요, 폴
I can handle reporters
on my own, Paul.
알아요, 내 기억하기론..
(Chuckles) Yeah, I know.
I remember.
사실, 저 여자를 보호했던 거에요
I was actually
looking out for her.
아마도 야구방망이를 싸왔겠죠
Maybe you packed
your baseball bat.
그를 떠난다고 어떻게 이야길 할 거에요?
How are you gonna tell him
you're leaving him?
아직 잘 모르겠어요
I don't know yet.
뭐가 잘못됐나요?
What's wrong?
샘은 당신에게 아직도 비밀을 가지고 있어요
Sam kept secrets from you.
난 그렇게 하기 싫어요
I don't want that.
그리고 내가 여기서 지금까지 한 행동들에 대해, 내가 , 음
And what I've been doing here,
I, uh...
다니엘이라는 아들이 하나 있어요
I have a son named Daniel.
굉장히 오랫동안 보질 못했죠
I haven't seen him
in a very long time.
미안해요
I'm sorry.
사랑하는 사람을 되찾기 위해
I just don't think
you understand
사람이 어떤 일을 할 수 있는 지를
what people are capable of
to get somebody back
당신이 이해할거라곤 생각하지 않아요
they love that much.
(Chuckles)
그래요, 폴
Yeah, Paul.
이해해요
I do.
이게 함정 같나요?
You think it's a trap?
글쎄, 내 부함장을 보트에서 데려가려고 하는데
Well, sure. Not only
do they have a reason
이유가 한가지만 있진 않겠지
to bring my XO
out to that boat,
그들의 행동에 영향을 미치는
they have the means
의미가 있겠지
to influence his actions.
제가 갈 이유가 없어요
I don't have to go.
가야해 하지만 알고 있게
Sure you do, but just know
그 배에 탄 이후 자네가 내게 이야기하는 어떤 말도
that whatever you say to me
from that boat
난 자네가 협박을 당하고 있다는 생각을 하고 참고하겠네
I'll consider to be
under duress.
뭔가 잘못되었어요
(Sophie) Oh, something's wrong.
저기, 저거 보여요?
There. Do you see that?
뭔데?
What?
이것이 사절단 보트의 음파 지문이에요
This is the signature
of the envoy boat.
그리고 여기 바닥아래로 부터 또 다른 음파지문이 있어요
And here is another one
just beneath the surface.
한 대의 배가 아니라 두 개란 뜻이죠
So it's not one vessel but two.
바로 아래에서부터 나오는 다른 것이라구요
One directly beneath the other.
(Metal clangs)
무슨 일이지?
What's happening?
(Gunfire)
(Screaming)
(Gunfire continues)
(Screaming continues)
신사숙녀 여러분
(Foreign accent)
Ladies and gentlemen,
여러분은 지금부터 파키스탄 해군의 포로가 되었습니다
you are now prisoners
of the Pakistani Navy.
At least what is left of it.
어떤 갑작스런 움직임도 하지 않기를 요청합니다
I ask that you do not
make any sudden movements
그리고 제가 이야기 한대로 정확히 그렇게 해 주십시오
and do exactly as I say.
메시지가 들어오고 있습니다
There's a message
coming through.
USS 콜로라도함의 마커스 채플린 함장은 들으시오
(Man) Captain Marcus Chaplin
of the USS Colorado,
이 보트와 당신 승조원의 가족들은
I have taken this boat
and with it,
내가 보호하고 있소
the families of your crew.
개인적으로 당신과 이야길 하고 싶소
I must speak to you in person.
잠수!!
Fall in!
잠수함에 타고 갈 전술타격팀의
I need
a tactical strike team ready
준비가 필요하다
by the time that man
boards my sub.
모든 승조원 중 고급 무기 훈련을 이수한
Every sailor with advanced
weapons training,
인원은 이 앞으로 나와라
step forward right now.
저희가 맡겠습니다 함장님
This is what we do, Captain.
5분안에 출발한다
We leave in five minutes.
코르테즈는 어디있나? 무기부사관은 어디있나?
Where's Cortez?
Where's the COB?!
무기부사관은 임무로 인해 불참입니다, 함장님
COB hasn't shown for duty, sir.
그를 기다릴 수는 없다, 출동!!
We can't wait for him.
Fall out!
(Panting)
(Door slams open)
(Indistinct murmuring)
함장님
Captain,
승객명단이 어디있나?
where is
your passenger manifest?
명단은 없습니다
I don't have a manifest.
이것은 자비로운 임무이다
This is a mission of mercy.
(Screams)
명단
Manifest.
제가.. 가져오겠습니다
I can-- I can get it.
잘 들어요
(Whispering) Listen to me,
명단을 이용해서 이용가치가 높은 인질을 고를 거에요
he'll use the manifest to choose
high-value hostages.
그들이 당신을 보게 할 수는 없어요
We can't let them see you.
제가 도울게요
I can help.
가요, 숨어요
Go. Hide.
선생님
_
저는 뉴스 기자입니다
제가 당신이 세상을 향해 이야기하도록 도울 수 있어요
_
요구사항이 뭔가요?
- 부함장님 - 어디 갔다오는거야?
- XO.
- Where the hell you been?
죄송합니다 부함장님
Sorry, sir.
글쎄, 지금은 죄송하다란 말로 충분할 것 같지 않은데
Yeah, well, sorry's
not good enough right now.
알겠어?
You understand me?
네, 부함장님. 전 준비되었습니다
(Pants) Yes, sir.
I'm here. I'm ready.
이봐
Hey.
메모리 카드들은 어디있지?
Where are the memory cards?
- 모르겠는걸 - 모르겠다고?
- Don't know.
- You don't know?
내가 오늘 정부의 어떤 핵심인물로 부터
I got a call today from somebody
very well-connected
전화를 한 통 받았는데
in the States.
우리가 지금 처한 이 지랄 맞은 상황이 이 헬멧카메라의 기록으로
Seems to think the footage
from those helmet-cams
모두 설명이 될 수도 있을 것이라는 데
might explain
this whole mess we're in.
내가 틀렸다고 말 하고 싶나?
You want to tell me I'm wrong?
우리가 지금 당장 좀 더 중요한 일을 해야 한다는 생각을 못하는것 같은데?
You don't think we got something
more important to do right now?
우리가 지금 뭘 해야 하는지 잘 알고 있어, 날 믿으라고
Oh, I know what we have to do.
Believe me.
우리가 지금 가서 우리 인질들을 구해야 한다는거 말야
So we're gonna go and we're
gonna save those hostages.
그리고 만약 우리가 돌아오게 될때
And if and when we come back,
그 메모리 카드를 내게 줬으면 해
you're gonna give me
those cards.
10분후에 임무 계획을 짜도록 하지
I want a mission plan
in ten minutes.
이건 우리 작전이야, 샘. 네 게 아니라구
This is our op, Sam.
Not yours.
여긴 내 잠수함이고 내 아내야
It's my sub and it's my wife.
나를 빼고 작전을 하고 싶다면
You don't want to take
orders from me,
섬까지 헤엄쳐서 돌아와야 할거야
you can swim
back to the island.
호프
Hop...
그것들이 어디있지?
where are they?
그것들은 안전해
They're safe.
BZ 공격후, 길의 시체 옆에 묻어 두었어
I buried 'em with Gil's body
after the BZ attack.
내가 그것에 대해 알야야 된다고 생각하지 않았어?
And you didn't think
I needed to know that?
지금 알게 되었잖아
You do now.
깨끗합니다, 함장님. 아무것도 없습니다
He's clean, sir.
Nothing on him.
사피르 아산 장군이네
Admiral Safir Ahsan.
마커스 채플린 함장이오
Captain Marcus Chaplin.
함장님이 지휘소에 오셨다
Captain on the conn.
아름답군
Beautiful.
길이 560피트
Length, 560 feet,
42 피트 빔
42-foot beam,
18,750 미터/톤의 배수량
displacing 18,750 metric tons.
아산 장군, 당신이 어떻게 생각하든
Admiral Ahsan,
whatever you may think,
내 배와 나 그리고 내 승조원,
I assure you,
this sub, me, my crew,
당신이 억류하고 있는 무고한 사람들과 배는
and the innocent people
you're holding on this boat
당신의 나라에 떨어진 폭탄과 아무 관계가 없다고 장담하오
had no part in the bombing
of your country.
내 나라?
My country?
국가라는 것은 국경이 있고
A country, sir, has borders.
군대가 있지요
A country has an army.
미국의 아군이었으나 핵 병기의 조준을 당하는 동안
A country does not tremble
on its knees
무릎을 꿇고 떨고만 있는 것이
while its nuclear arsenal
is locked down
한 국가라고 할 수는 없지요
by the allies
of the United States.
우리가 파키스탄에 발사하지 않았소, 장군
We didn't fire
on Pakistan, Admiral.
우린 그 명령을 거부했단 말이오
We refused the order.
알아요 그렇기 때문에 내가 여기 온거요
Yes, I know.
That's why I'm here.
함장님
(Man) Sir.
(Screams)
안되요 안되요
No. No, no, no.
2분 남았소
You have two minutes.
뭘 원하는 것이오
What do you want?
어제 인도 장군 프라나브 밧나가로프가
Yesterday an Indian general
named Pranav Bhatnagar
그의 기갑여단을 몰고 침략했오
mobilized his armed brigade.
한 시간안에 그는 국경을 넘어 돌아가야하오
In a matter of hours,
he will cross the border
내 조국, 카시미르를 떠나서 말이오
out of Kashmir,
into my country.
함장님
(Grace) Sir.
우리 군은 조각나 있고, 우리 핵 무기는 압류되었소
With our military fractured,
our nuclear weapons seized,
이 도살자를 돌려보낼 수 있는
Pakistan has now nothing
that would pose
어떤 효과적인 위협수단이 현재 파키스탄에는 없소
a sufficient threat to make
this butcher turn back.
그래요 우린 할 수 있소
Yes, but we do.
그래요 당신들은 할 수 있오
Yes, you do.
그 들 침입자들에게 트라이던트 D-5
You will fire one trident
D-5 nuclear missile
핵 미사일중 한개를 발사한다면
at those invaders,
또는 사절보트에 있는 내 중위가 강제로..
or my lieutenant on that boat
will be forced--
무고한 시민을 죽일 수는 없을 것이오
You cannot begin by killing
innocent civilians.
일 분이오
One minute.
무고한 시민이란 말은 파키스탄에는 더 이상 통용되지 않을것이오
And don't lecture a Pakistani
about innocent civilians.
시간이 좀 더 필요하오
I need more time.
함장님, 보트에 제 부모님이 계세요
Sir, my parents
are on that boat.
지휘소의 모든 사람은 생각을 입밖에 내지 않도록
Everyone on the conn will keep
their thoughts to themselves.
(Speaking foreign language)
뭐야? 뭐라고 말하는거지?
What? What is he saying?
(Gunshot) (Screaming)
(Gasps)
안돼
No.
다음 차례까지 30분 남았소
You have 30 minutes
until the next.
셰퍼드 카힐 중위, 지휘소를 봉쇄해
Lieutenant Shepard,
Cahill, lock down the conn.
꼭 필요한 사람만 빼고
Essential personnel only.
내가 이 일을 반대했다는 것을 알려주고 싶소
I want you to know
that I despise this.
내가 하고자 했던 것들과 반대로 돌아가고 있소
It goes against everything
that I am,
바닷사람으로, 무슬림으로, 아빠로서
as a seaman, as a Muslim,
as a father.
애들이 있소?
You have children?
이슬라마바드에
Islamabad.
공격이 일어났던때 도시 북쪽에
My son Malik was at school
말릭이란 아들이 학교에 있었소
north of the city
when the strike happened.
나 또한 아들을 잃었소
I also lost a son.
하지만 항상 희망은 있소, 항상
But there's always hope.
Always.
당신의 아들의 죽음에 대해 그들이 이야기 할때
And when they told you
about your son,
그때도 당신은 희망이 있었소?
did you hope then?
전화를 몇 통 해야 겠소
I need to make some calls.
29분 남았소
You have 29 minutes.
셰퍼드 중위, 지휘소를 맡게
Lieutenant Shepard,
you have the conn.
(Gunshot) (Screaming)
(Gasping)
오 세상에
(Man) Oh, my God.
함장님이 우리 가족들이 죽게 내버려 두지 않을거야
The Captain's not just gonna
let 'em kill our families,
그렇지?
is he?
네 동생
Your brother,
많이 움직이지 않던데, 그렇지 않아?
the kid hasn't seen
much action, has he?
맞아
No.
카말은 뭔가 다른 일을 했어야만 해
No, Kamal should've been
something different.
그런데 왜 이런일을 하고 있어?
But what are you going to do?
우리가 항상 우리길을 선택할수는 없잖아?
We can't always
be choosing our paths. Hmm?
그는 가족이 있어, 나 처럼
He has family, just like I do.
넌 퇴역군인이지?
You're ex-military.
퇴역은 아니고, 단지 임명과 퇴역 중간 쯤이지
Not ex.
Just in between assignments.
너네 지휘관이 그게 괜찮다고 그래?
And your command
is okay with that?
전부터 내 동생과 나는
My brother and I,
일을 함께 해 왔었어
we've done jobs
together before--
아프카니스탄에서 운송사업도 하고
Transport in and out
of Afghanistan,
이라크에서 경호관련 일도 했지
security details
with contractors in Iraq.
우린 좋아
We're fine.
저기 있는 우리 박사는 말이야
Our doctor down there,
그가 세상을 바꿀수 있다고 생각해
he thinks
he's changed the world.
Mm-hmm.
그도 술을 마시고 있네
He's also been drinking.
저 박사와 내 동생, 정말 비슷해, 알고 있어?
The doctor, my brother,
very similar, you know?
그들 둘 다 커다란 것을 믿고 있지
They both like to believe
big things.
넌 아니고?
Not you?
(Swallows)
아니
No.
아니야
(Sets canteen down)
난 너처럼 군인인걸
I am a soldier like you are.
(Faint radio chatter)
명령이 내려졌어
Order's in.
경로를 확인해, 밖에서 5분뒤에 보자
Check the route.
Meet you back in five.
좋아
Right.
자 보자
Now look.
이해하길 바래요
I want you to understand,
당신과 내가 여기에서 중요한 일을 했다는거죠
you and I did something
important here.
느낌이 좋아
It is a good feeling.
진짜 좋은데Almost as goodas beating you at gin. (Laughs)
Almost as good
as beating you at gin. (Laughs)
- 우리 떠나는게 확실한가요? - 곧
- Are we clear to leave?
- Soon.
네, 알겠습니다
Yes, sir. Understood.
(Receiver clatters) (Exhales)
그 물질 재료가 내게 있다
I have the materials.
녹화 시작
Recording on.
우린 한편의 쇼를 원하네, 병사
(Man) We need a full show,
soldier--
발견, 설명
Discovery, description.
미국을 위해 공연을 하는거네, 병사
You're performing for
the United Nations now, son.
역사를 위한 것이기도 하지
This one's for history.
베리 호퍼, 일급 상사
Petty Officer First Class
Barry Hopper.
파키스탄 저항군의 상당한 저항에도 불구하고
Despite substantial Pakistani
military resistance,
우리는 휴대용 핵분열 물질을 발견했습니다
we have uncovered portable
fissionable material.
이것들이 휴대용 이동용 핵 무기입니다
These are compact,
mobile nuclear weapons,
또는 서류가방형 폭탄에 이용됩니다
or suitcase bombs.
닐스워스 박사의 시도는 실패하였습니다
Our attempt to exfil Dr. Nils
was unsuccessful
파키스탄 군부의 작적으로인해 그는 사살되었으..
as he was killed by Pakistani
military operat--
뭐하고 있어?
What are you doing?
호프, 그건 어디서 났어?
Hop, where did you get
that stuff, man?
나중에 제임스
Not now, James.
새로운 명령이야
New orders.
호프 무슨일이야?
Hop, what's going on?
함장님
Captain,
300야드 안에 저희를 이송해주십시오
you get us within 300 yards,
탈출해치로 이동해서 스쿠버로 이동하겠습니다
we lock and scuba out
the forward escape hatch.
보트 뒤쪽으로 접근 탑승한 이후
Come off to the back of
the boat,
처리하도록 하겠습니다
and work our way up.
Take out the marks on the perimeter주변을 정리한 이후
Take out the marks
on the perimeter
우리중 한명이 저격할 수 있도록 하겠습니다
for one of us
to get a clean shot.
12명의 적군이 있는것으로 예상됩니다
We think there's 12 men
on board.
최악을 보고 있다네
We've seen worse.
다음 희생자가 나올때까지 30분이 남았어
We have less than 30 minutes
until the next deadline.
30분안에 해치우긴 어렵습니다
30 minutes ain't gonna cut it.
장군을 설득하든지 아님 또 다른 희생자가 나올 뿐이겠지
Either you talk him down,
or there's another body.
시간이 없군요
We're wasting time.
그럼 가자구
Let's go, then.
- 샘 - 네?
- Sam.
- Yeah?
확실하게 하려고 내 최선을 다하겠네만
I'm gonna try my best
to make sure
씰팀과 자네들이 해결 하지 못할 수도 있어
this doesn't come down
to you and the SEALs.
저는 쉬운 부분을 맡는거고, 함장님이 어려운 부분을 맡는겁니다
Hey, I got the easy part.
You got the hard part.
장군을 설득하셔야 되요
You gotta talk that man down.
크리스틴이 배에 있지 않나
Christine's on board.
다른 부인들도 그 배에 많이 있어요
A lot of wives are on board.
(Sighs)
여기요
Here.
(Key clinks)
행운을 빌어요
Good luck.
행운을 빈다
내가 숙지해야 될 내용은?
So what do I need to know?
6개월 씰 훈련과정을 5분안에 나보고 쑤셔넣어달라고?
You want me to jam six months
of SEAL training
이봐 난 어떻게 싸우는지
- into five minutes?
- Look, I know how to fight
방아쇠를 어떻게 당기는 지 알고 있다고
and I know
how to pull a trigger.
거기에 내가 해야될 일이 있으면 뭐든지 기꺼이 할 준비가 되었으니까
Besides that, I am willing
to do anything that I have to.
뭐가 더 필요하지?
What else is there?
당신을 위해 그녈 꼭 구해내도록 하지
We'll get her back
for you, man.
이봐, 내가 이일을 해야돼, 네가 아니라
Hey. I have to do this.
You don't.
그래서 고마워
So thank you.
(Chuckles)
농담해?
Are you kidding?
세상을 위해 거래하는게 아냐
I wouldn't trade this
for the world.
여기에 사인해 줘서 고마워
Hey. Thank you
for signing for this,
어쨌거나, 입을게 하나도 없었는데
otherwise I wouldn't have
had anything to wear.
내가 준비한거 아냐, 하녀껀데 그거
I didn't. It was the maid.
사실, 여기에서 널 보게된게 조금 놀라워
In fact, I'm a little surprised
to see you here.
글쎄, 아빠가 항상 말씀하셨지 "가족이 첫번째다"
Well, dad always says,
"family comes first."
아빠가 그렇게 말씀은 하셨지
Yeah. He does say that.
기분이 좋지 않나봐 그치?
Doesn't feel good, does it,
아웃사이더 중의 하나가 된거 말야
being the one on the outside,
네 큰 오빠가 지금 얼마나 크려고 노력하고 있는지 아니?
struggling to measure up
to your big brother now?
난 바이올린은 다 잊어버렸는데, 지금은 그거라도 해야될거야(오빠가 비즈니스는 할 줄 아는게 없다는 놀림)
Aw. Would you look at that?
I forgot my violin.
근데 조율하는 법은 기억하고 있지않아?
Fortunately, you already have
the tune memorized.
오 잘들어
Oh, listen,
데프코 그룹의 데렉 웨스트가 Derek West from the Defco group
Derek West from the Defco group
오늘밤 여기 올거야
is gonna be here tonight.
우리 회사에 그가 큰 투자를 하도록
We are looking to broker
a very big deal
정말 큰 협상을 위한 브로커를 찾고 있어
with his investment firm.
그런데 우연히도
And coincidentally,
그가 너한테 꽤 호감을 갖고 있다고 들었거든
I'm told he has
quite a crush on you.
조금만 도와줄수 있지?
Lead him on a little, will ya?
회사를 위해서말야
For the good of the company.
런던의 제휴사인 레나 카푸아로부터,
(Man) Rena Kapur
from our affiliate in London,
세인트 마리나섬으로 향하던 평화를 위한 보트 갑판에서
reading terrorist demands
from the deck
테러리스트의 요구조건이 밝혀집니다
of the peacekeeping boat
to Sainte Marina.
인도 수상은 유엔안전보장이사회에서 사인한..
Indian President Singhs spoke to
the UN Secu--
자네가 인도를 향해서 미사일을 발사하는 건에 대해 심각하게
(Curry) Tell me you're not
seriously considering
생각하지 않는다고 말해주게
launching against India.
상원의원님, 제가 그들의 조건에 응하지 않는다면
Mr. Secretary, if I don't
comply with their demands,
40명의 저희 사랑하는 가족들이 저희 눈앞에서
40 of our loved ones
will be killed
죽임을 당할것입니다
right before our very eyes.
저들은 미군 가족들입니다
These are American
military families.
이런일 때문에 핵 잠수함을 탈취해서
This is why you don't hijack
a nuclear submarine
다른나라와의 정책을 망치도록 못하게 하려한 것이네
and try to conduct
rogue foreign policy.
그들은 무고한 미국인들입니다
These are innocent Americans.
그들을 도울 방법은 전혀 없나요?
Are you going to do anything
at all to help them?
네이비씰팀이 한시간 거리에 준비하고 있네
I have a SEAL team an hour out.
내가 할 수 있는 최선이 그것이네
It's the best I can do.
그런 많은 시간적 여유가 없습니다
These hostages
don't have that much time.
내가 할 수 있는 최선이 그것이네
It's the best I can do.
인도에 이렇게 이야기하는 것은 어떤가요
Then you had better tell India
마커스 채플린이 무슨짓을 할지 전혀 모르겠다고
that Marcus Chaplin has no idea
what he's gonna do.
그쪽 장군은 철수해야 할것입니다
Their general
should stand down.
콜로라도 통신끝
Colorado out.
DC와 통화를 했었소
I've been on the phone with DC,
밧나가로프 장군이 회군하도록 압력을 넣겠다고 했소
and they will pressure Bhatnagar
to turn back.
당신 친구에게 내가 무척 감사한다고 전해 주시오
Please tell your friends
that I do appreciate
내 조국에 대해 그들의 모든 노력에 대해서도
all their efforts
on behalf of my country.
하지만 내가 확답을 듣기 전까지는..
But until I receive
confirmation about--
카힐 중위, 사절단 보트를 연결해
Lieutenant Cahill,
hail the envoy boat,
통신선로를 올려
raise the bridge.
당신 부하를 불러서
Call up your men
한시간이 필요하다고 말하시오
and tell them I need one hour.
함장, 당신이 이해를 하지 못하고 있소
Captain, you do not understand.
내가 여기 있는 이유는
There is a reason why I'm here
보트위 내 중위가 모든 권한이 있기 때문이요
and my lieutenant is in charge
on that boat.
그가 끔찍한 행위들의 책임자요
He's a man capable
of terrible acts.
이 메카니즘은 멈추지 않을것이요
A mechanism that will not stop
결과를 얻을 때까지..
until the result
is achieved--
내 독립주권국인 파키스탄에서
The removal of Indian forces
인도군이 없어질때까지 !!
from my sovereign nation
of Pakistan!
당신은 민족주의자가 아니요, 테러리스트지
You're not a nationalist.
You're a terrorist.
내가요?
Am I?
그렇다면 무엇이 당신을 이렇게 행동하게 만들었소?
And what does that make you?
젠장 마이크를 들어요!!
Take the damn mic!
난 그를 멈출 힘이 없소
I don't have the power
to stop him.
오직 당신만이 할 수 있소
Only you do.
셰퍼드 중위
Lieutenant Shepard,
발사 심도로 잠항하게
take us to launch depth.
함장님?
(Grace) Sir?
넵 함장님
Aye, sir.
헬름, 2-3 방향으로
Helm, all ahead two-thirds.
심도 5도로 잠항한다
Dive 5-degree down angle.
발사심도로 진행 후 대기한다
Proceed to launch depth
and hover the boat.
내 조국이 공격받았을때
When my country was hit,
난 망연자실했었다오
I was devastated.
움직일수도 없었고
I couldn't move.
바닥에 누워서 생각을 했었지
I would lay on the floor
and think...
이런 힘에 맞서 한사람이
What could one man possibly do
할 수 있는 가능한 일이 무얼까?
in the face of all this power?
그러나 난 목소리를 들었소
But then I heard a voice.
그리고 거기에 당신이 있었지
And there you were,
카메라 앞에 서서
standing before that camera,
모든 불의에 맞서서
standing against all injustice.
당신, 마커스 채플린...
You, Marcus Chaplin...
당신이 나를 내 비겁함으로 부터 구한거요
you saved me
from my own cowardice.
그리고 그제서야 난 알았지
And I knew then...
한 사람이 세상을 바꿀수 있다는 것을
that one man
can change the world.
발사 심도입니다, 함장님
(Grace) Launch depth, Captain.
무기실, 지휘소다
Weapons, conn.
미사일 발사구를 열어
Open missile doors.
(Mic clatters)
(Key clicks)
다른 키 하나는 어디있소?
Where is the other key?
내 부함장한테 있소
With my XO.
인질의 반을 풀어주면 두번째 키를 볼 수 있을 것이오
You want to see the second key,
you give me half the hostages.
내가 설명한대로, 협상은 없소
As I explained,
there is no bargaining.
내가 발사한 다음에도 모두 죽이지 않을지
How do I know he's not
going to kill them all
내가 어떻게 알 수 있소?
after I fire?
신념을 보여주려면
You give me half
the family members
가족들중 절반을 풀어주시오
off that boat
as a show of faith,
그럼 나도 내 미사일을 당신에게 주겠소
and I will give you
your missile.
당신이 테러리스트가 아니라고 말한다면
You say you're not a terrorist.
이를 증명하시오
Prove it.
좋아요 함장
Very well, Captain.
노력해 보겠소
I will try.
(Sighs)
여자들을 보내줘라
_
우리세계의 명예를 보여주기 위해서
당신이 그렇게 굽힐 줄 알았습니다
_
밧나가로프가 문제의 핵심일 뿐이야여자들은 구명정으로 보내, 이건 명령이야
그가 뭐라고 하나요?
What did he say?
그는 고집불통이요, 음..
He's stubborn, but, uh--
(Gunshot) Oh!
(Screaming) Aah!
그를 멈출 수 있는 건 오직 당신뿐이라고 내가 말하지 않았소
I told you! There is only
one way to stop him.
발사해요, 발사해야만 해요, 함장
You must fire.
You must fire, Captain.
발사하란 말이오
You have to fire!
오 세상에
Oh, my God.
(Screaming)
뭘 기다리고 있는거야
What the hell
is he waiting for?
다른 어떤 장군놈한테 쏘는 것 보다
Is he gonna let
our families die
우리 가족이 죽어나가는 것을 보고만 있을건가
rather than fire
on some other general?
(Clatters)
이봐 이봐
Hey. Hey.
그들을 구출할 다른 방법이 진행되고 있을거야, 알았어?
(Crying) There's gonna be some
kind of rescue on the way, right?
우린 여기 아래에서 우리 일을 하고
We do our jobs,
keep it together down here,
함장님은 저기 위에서 그의 일을 하는거야
and the captain can do
his job up there.
더 이상은 아무도 죽지 않을거야
No one else is gonna die.
부함장님, 시간이 없습니다
XO, we are running out of time.
상태가 어떤가요?
What's your status?
방금 승선했고, 아직 접촉은 없었다
(Lowered voice)
On board. No contact yet.
(Snaps)
대부분 적군이 갑판에 있는것 같다
(James) Looks like it's mostly
the guys on deck.
복도가 안전한지 확인해봐
Make sure that
starboard corridor is clear.
알았나?
You copy?
알았다
Yeah, copy.
갑판에 3명확인
I got three on the deck.
방금 출입구쪽 복도에 한명 나가는 것 확인Just took out one port side corridor.
Just took out
one portside corridor.
확인
(Hopper) Copy.
석궁으로 한명 해치웠다
I've got one bogey
down on the bow.
우현 위쪽에 한명, 조금 곤란한데 샘?
One left up top starboard,
but it's messy. Sam?
우현 복도에서 2명 확인
I've got two
in the starboard corridor
주 갑판으로 향하는 중
heading towards the main deck.
호프
Hop.
뭐하는 거야?
What are you doing?
- 꼬마야 넌 비켜 - 아니, 안돼
- Out of the way, kid. Now.
- No, you can't--
안돼!, 집에서 겨우 5클릭거리야
No! We are five klicks
from home.
- 네가 이해를 못하고 있어- 집에 다 왔다구
- You don't understand.
- We're almost home!
(Footsteps approach)
(Pants)
(Indistinct conversations)
안녕
Hello.
Mm.
마실거?
Drinks?
네, 부탁해요
Yes, please.
데렉, 내 동생 카일리 기억하지?
Derek, you remember
my sister Kylie.
안녕하세요
Hello.
아빠, 데렉 기억하죠
Dad, you remember Derek,
조지타운에서 동아리 선배였어요
my fraternity brother
at Georgetown
그리고 데프코 그룹의 파트너이구요
and a partner
at the Defco group.
만나서 반갑구나
Good to see you, son.
- 음료를 가져오지 - 네
- Let's get some drinks.
- Yes.
저걸로 끝나지 않을거야
That's not gonna end well.
왜 그렇게 말하죠?
Why do you say that?
정부가 마커스 채플린을 돕는일엔
The government isn't gonna
lift a finger
손가락도 하나 움직이지 않을 거니까
to help Marcus Chaplin.
테러리스트와 함께 누워서
He put himself
in bed with terrorists,
그들과 함께 묻히겠지
he'll bury himself with this,
그리고 워싱턴의 내친구들이 그렇게 할테고
and our boys in Washington
will let him.
당신 친구들이요?
Our boys?
당신 친구들이 전국 텔레비전에서 유권자들이 그들 자신들의
I don't think our boys
want to see
친구들의 머리가 날아가는 것을 보고 싶어하지는
their own constituents have
their brains blown out
않을 것 같은데요
on national television.
그들은 우리 사람이 아니에요
Those are not our men in arms.
그들은 역적들이죠, 간단해요
They're traitors,
plain and simple.
당신은 아주 확신하는 군요
You're very sure of yourself.
마커스 채플린이 미국의 자산을 훔치지 않았다면
Those terrorists wouldn't be
ransoming lives for nukes
그 테러리스들이 핵을 위해서 그렇게 난리를 칠 것 같아요?
if Marcus Chaplin hadn't stolen
United States property.
당신이 제안하는 건 뭔가요?
So what would you propose?
잠수함과 사절보트를 날려버리는거죠
Blow the boat, blow the sub,
손실을 없애고 끝맺음 하는 거죠
cut their losses,
and be done with it.
만일 그렇지 않는다면 매주 이번과 같은 다른일들을 보게 될거에요
If not, every week, we're gonna
see something else just like it.
한 사람이 책임질 수는 없죠
One man can't be responsible
대다수의 잘 사는 사람들을 위해서라도
for the well-being
of people everywhere.
아니요, 우리 같은 사람들이 남아야 된다는 거 아닌가요?
No, it should be left
to people like us, right?
당신이 먼저 말했네요
You said it first.
상황을 해결하기 위한 신속하고 결정적인 조치를
Saying, they are taking
swift and decisive action
취할 것이라고 이야기 하고 있습니다
to defuse the situation.
위성이미지는 지금 현재 밧나가로프 장군이
As of this moment,
satellite images
여전히 진격하고 있음을..
still show
General Bhatnagar heading...
당신 인도인이군
You are Indian.
전 영국인이에요, 런던에서 태어났죠
I'm British.
I was born in London.
그렇다고 피가 달라지진 않지
That doesn't change your blood.
카메라 켜
Turn that on.
인도를 향해 메시지가 있거든
I have a new message for India.
인도인들은 파키스탄에서 환영받지 못할 것이다
Indians are not welcome
in Pakistan.
안돼요 제발요 저는 당신이 원하는 사람이 아니에요
(Voice breaking) No, please.
I'm not the one you want.
저는 당신이 원하는 사람이 아니에요
크리스틴 켄달..
Christine Kendal...
그녀가 당신이 원하는 사람이에요
she's the one you want.
그녀가 부함장의 아내에요
She's the wife
of the executive officer
USS 콜로라도함의
on the USS Colorado.
그녀를 데려가세요, 그녈 구하기 위해 어떤것이라도 할거에요
If you take her, they'll do
whatever you ask.
제발요
Please.
그녀가 옳아
She's right.
내가 크리스틴 켄달이고 저들은 필요치 않을거야
I'm Christine Kendal,
and you don't want them.
내가 당신이 원하는 모든것이니까
I am all you need.
미안해요
(Whispers) I'm so sorry.
이걸 내놔
Give me this.
여기 기자 양반
Here, journalist.
이게 당신을 유명하게 해줄거야
This will make you famous.
그가 영화를 찍으려는군
He makes a move,
내가 그를 잡겠다, 준비됐어
I am taking him out,
so be ready.
하퍼가 아직 위치에 있지 않아요
(James)
Hopper is not in position.
당신이 쏘면, 모두 죽을거에요
You go now, everybody dies.
저기 내 부함장의 아내가 있군
That is the wife
of my Executive Officer.
네 부하에게 알려줘, 만약 그녀를 죽인다면
Let your man know
if he kills her,
밧나가로프 장군을 되돌릴 방법을 영영 잃어버릴거라고
he loses any chance
of turning back Bhatnagar.
그는 듣질 않을거에요
He won't listen.
그런 괴물과 어떻게 같이 행동하게 되었지?
How do you align yourself
with such a monster?
그는 괴물이 아니요
He's not a monster.
우린 모두 거친 세상를 알게 해준 라사리의
We were both sons
of poor fishermen in Lasari
가난한 어부의 자식들이라오
who have learned the harsher
realities of the world.
그가 이미 저지른것들과 하려는 것 모두
What he's already done,
what he's about to do,
괴물만이 할 수 있는 일이오
only a monster could.
당신이 발사하지 않는다면 그녀는 어찌되었건 죽을거요
If you don't launch,
she's dead anyway.
만약 밧나가로프가 파키스탄을 계속 진격한다면
If Bhatnagar crosses
into Pakistan,
그들 모두 죽을 것이요
they all are.
여기 서
Stand here.
거의 정리되었다, 곧 위치로 가겠다
(Hopper) Almost clear.
Coming into position.
60초 남았다
Need 60 seconds.
잠깐만 잠깐
(Paul) Wait! Wait.
쏘지 마시오
Don't shoot.
- 넌 누구냐? - 내 이름은 폴 웰이요
- Who are you?
- My name is Paul Wells.
내가 당신을 도울수 있어요
I can help you.
당신이 우려하는 그 인도 장군에 대해서요..
That-- that general
in India you're worried about,
그를 되돌아가게끔 할 수 있어요, 단지 전화 한통이면 되요
I can make that go away
with just one phone call.
오, 그래? 네가 그렇게 할 수 있다는 거지?
Oh, really?
Just how will you do that?
미국정부를 대신하는 대리인 자격이 있어요
(Pants) I'm an attorney for
the United States Government.
당신 나라에서 일어나는 일에 대해 책임질 수 있는
I work directly
for the people responsible
사람 바로 밑에서 일하고 있다구요
for what happened
to your country.
그들은 내말을 들을거에요
They will listen to me.
알았죠? 그녈 놔주고 내가 전화하게 해줘요
Okay? Just let her go
and I'll call them.
당신이 원한걸 내가 해줄 수 있다구요..
I-I-I can get you
what you need.
미국정부가 파키스탄을 돕는다고?
The American Government
wants to help Pakistan?
아무쪼록
By all means.
부함장님 나오세요
(Grace) XO, come in.
샘?
Sam?
킹이에요
This is King.
그 장군이 파키스탄을 가로지르고 있어요
The general is about to cross
into Pakistan,
그렇게 된다면 모두를 다 죽일거에요
if that happens,
he will kill them all.
지금 움직여야 될거에요
You need to move now.
안돼요, 아직 위치를 선점하지 못했어요
Negative.
We do not have position.
내 상관에게 전화하게만 해줘요
(Paul) Okay, just let me
call my superiors,
그럼 우리가 당신의 요구사랑을 바로 들어줄것이에요
and we can make your demands
to them directly.
하퍼 위치완료
Hopper set.
피쉬 어디야?
(James) Fish, where are you?
내가 도울 수 있어요
I can help you.
US 정부가 인도에 압력을 넣을 수 있어요
The US Government
will put pressure on India,
그 장군은 다른 방도가 없을 거에요
and that-- that general
won't have a choice.
절 믿어요
Trust me.
(Screaming)
폴! 폴!
Paul! Paul!
(Gasps)
(Exhales)
폴 이봐요
(Groans) Paul, hey.
(Groans) Hey.
(Pants)
미안해요, 당신에게 거짓말을 했어요
I'm sorry I lied to you.
아니에요 아니에요, 상관없어요
No, no.
No, that doesn't matter.
조금만 참아요
Just... just hold on.
Okay?
DC에 사람이 있어요
There's a man in DC...
루카스 벤더라고
Lucas Bender.
난 정말 당신이 괜찮길 바랬어요
I just want you to be okay.
당신이 날 구했어요
(Crying) You saved me.
(Groans)
고마워요
Thank you.
(Sniffles)
일어나
(Man) Get up.
(Cries and sniffles)
(Huffs)
좋아 여러분
(James) Okay, people.
목표를 해치운다
Acquire targets.
5분이 지났소, 시간이 다 되었소
Five minutes.
You're running out of time.
당신이 발사하지 않으면 계속해서 일어날 일들이오
This will happen
unless you launch.
미사일을 발사해야 할거요
You have to fire that missile.
그럴수 없소
I can't.
이런 야만적인 행위를 이행하라고 당신에게 요청하는게 아니요
I'm not asking you to perform
this savage act for me.
이건 복수가 아니오 마커스
This is not vengeance, Marcus.
이건 내 조국을 위한 구원이오
This is salvation
for my nation.
아니, 내 말은
No, I mean...
난 할 수 없다는..
I cannot.
(Clicks)
함장님 발사명령 대기 중입니다
Captain, ready to launch
on your order.
4분 남았소
(Ahsan) Four minutes.
함장님 명령 대기중입니다
Awaiting your orders, Captain.
부함장과 킹이 공작에 묶여서
XO and King are tied up
in engineering.
저희를 도울 수 없을것 같습니다
They can't help us.
(Chuckles)
밧나가로프의 부대가 얼마나 크나?
How large is Bhatnagar's force?
인원 수가 얼마나 되지?
How many men?
얼마냐고?
How many?
이게 당신의 숙면을 위한다면
If it helps you sleep better,
몇 백쯤 되요, 천은 되지 않을 거요
hundreds, not thousands.
무기실, 지휘소다, 4번 미사일 준비
Weapons, conn.
Spin up missile four.
1-SQ로 셋팅
Set condition to 1-SQ.
(Whirring)
일어나
Get up.
지금
Now!
여기 서
Stand here.
좋아 내 확인에 따라 진행한다
(James) Okay, we go on my mark.
잠깐 무전이 들어온다
Hold on.
He's on the radio.
네
Yes.
USS 콜로라도의 마커스 채플린 함장이다
This is Captain Marcus Chaplin
of the USS Colorado.
발사 준비가 완료 되었다
I'm prepared to launch.
보고 있겠소
I'm watching.
아니 넌 실수했다
No, you mistake me.
내 미사일은 밧나가로프 장군을 겨냥하지 않는다
My missile is not aimed
at General Bhatnagar.
네 고향, 나사리를 겨냥하고 있다
It's aimed at your hometown
of Lasari.
뭐 하자는 거요?
What are you doing?
당신 가족과 그의 가족들을
I'm putting your family
in the cross fire,
십자가 불속에 놓을것이요
and his.
모든 인질을 안전하게 풀어주는데 2분 주겠다
You have two minutes to release
all the hostages safely
아니면 나사리로 미사일을 쏴 주지
or I will launch on Lasari.
더 이상 협상은 없다
There will be
no further negotiations.
피쉬 완료
(Fisher) Fish, set.
이제 우리 차례군
This is our shot.
내 사격에 시작해
On my go.
워싱턴에서 연결되었습니다 함장님
(Cahill) Washington
on the line, sir.
채플린이다
This is Chaplin.
위성으로 미사일 사구가 열린게 탐지되었다는데
(Curry) Satellite shows
your missile doors opening.
도대체 뭘 하고 있는건가?
What the hell are you doing?
인도를 향해 발사 하지 말게
Do not fire at India.
파키스탄에서 철수하라고 이야기 하시오
Tell them not to cross
into Pakistan.
콜로라도 통신 끝
Colorado out.
(Receiver clatters)
씨호크 2대가 들어옵니다 함장님, 반 마일 거리입니다
Two seahawks inbound, sir,
half a mile out.
씰팀입니다
It's their SEAL team.
(Helicopter blades whirring)
발사
Go.
(Gunfire)
(Gasping and screaming)
카말?
Kamal?
(Groans)
이 사람들은 이렇게 되서는 안돼
These people
didn't deserve this.
(Gunshot)
내 사람은 내 동생은 어떻게 할 건데?
What about my people,
my brother?!
그들은 그래도 되고?
Did they?
(Gunshot)
(Helicopter blades whirring)
(People shouting indistinctly)
샘?
Sam?
배 위에 다른 팀들이 있다
(Hopper)
We got company on board.
샘?
Sam!
- 크리스틴 - 피셔
- Christine!
- Fisher!
미안해
(Fisher) I'm sorry, man.
새로운 명령이야, 그녀가 내 고향행 티켓이라고
New orders.
She's my ticket home.
피셔 뭘하는 거야?
What the hell are you doing,
Fisher?
어디로 그녈 데려가는 거냐고?
Where are you taking her?!
안돼요, 철수해야되요
No! We gotta go.
잘못했다간 그녀가 죽어요 어서요
You are no good to her dead.
Come on!
(Whirring continues)
US 해군에서 상황이 끝났다고 통신을 보냈습니다
US Navy reporting
situation secure.
모든 테러리스트들이 제거되거나 체포되었습니다
All terrorists
killed or captured.
함장님 보시죠
Sir, look.
밧나가로프 장군이 퇴각합니다
General Bhatnagar's retreating.
- 미사일 사구를 닫게 - 네 함장님
- Close our missile doors.
(Cahill) - Yes, sir.
(Clanks)
부함장과 씰대원들이 돌아오면 알려주게
Let me know when the XO
and our SEALs are back on board.
- 넵 함장님 - 포로 인계 준비하고
- Aye, sir.
- And prepare to hand over
아산토 장군은 해군당국에 인계한다
Admiral Ahsan
to naval authorities.
네 함장님
Yes, sir.
인도정부는 이번 주권독립국가인 파키스탄에 대한
(Man) General Bhatnagar has
been relieved of his command
"불법적인 임무"를 수행한 행위에 대해 밧나가로프 장군을
following what
the Indian Government
직위해제 하였습니다
is now calling "a rogue charge
이번 사건으로 들어난 마커스 채플린함장은
towards the sovereign nation
of Pakistan."
승조원 가족들이 학살자에게 살해되는 와중에도
It appears that Marcus Chaplin
was content to allow
이를 용인하는 태도를 보였으며
the slaughter
of his crew's families,
유일하게 이를 대응했던 행동은 US 네이비씰팀으로
and that only action
by the US Navy SEALs
이보다 더 훌륭할 수는 없는..
prevented
an even greater--
네가 여기 있을것 같았다
I thought
I might find you here.
네, 아빠
Hi, dad.
네가 무도회에서 돌아왔을때와 같은 모습이구나
You look just like you did when
you got back from your prom.
(Chuckles)
그때도 여기에서 널 발견했지
Found you here, just like that,
아이스크림을 몽땅 먹으면서
over a tub of ice cream
모든 다른 아이들 처럼 파티에 나가지 않고
instead of out partying
with all the other kids.
네가 네 친구들을 정말 좋아하지 않는것을
Said you realized
깨달았다고 말했었지
that you didn't actually
like your friends.
내가 뭐라고 이야기 했는지 기억하니?
Remember what I told you?
걔네들을 좋아할 필요는 없지만
You said
I didn't have to like 'em,
걔네들이 필요할거라고 말씀하셨죠
but I would need them.
무슨 충고가 그래요?
(Clicks tongue and chuckles)
What kind of advice is that?
내가 맞지 않았나?
Was I right?
10대 소녀에게 할 이야긴 아니죠
That doesn't mean you say that
to a teenage girl.
(Sighs)
어쨌든 전 친구들이 있어요
Anyway, I have friends.
친구 하나요
A friend. (Sighs)
(Pours liquid)
아빠, 전 아빠처럼 주위를 그렇게 자르지 못하겠어요
Dad, I'm not cut out
like the rest of you.
아냐
No.
넌 나보다 낫다
You're better.
우린 무기를 만들잖니 카일리
We make weapons, Kylie.
네가 생각하기에 내가 그것들과 씨름하지 않는것 같니?
You-- you think
I don't wrestle with that?
사실은 네가 그것들을 아직도 신경쓰고 있다는 거야
So the fact that you
still care about that...
그건 내가 널 믿을 수 있다는 거란다
That means
that I can trust you.
- 아빠 - 우린 긴긴 싸움을 하는거란다 카일리
- Dad--
- We play the long game, Kylie.
넌 결코 탈락하지 않을 거야
You're never out.
단지 재계산을 할 뿐이지
You're just recalculating.
(Indistinct conversations)
제가 발사키를 가져 가지 않았습니다 함장님
I didn't take
your firing key, sir.
단지 발견했을 뿐이겠지
You just found it.
그렇습니다
That's right.
그게 구석에 걸려있었습니다
It was hanging in plain sight.
절 믿지 않으시군요, 거짓말 탐지기를 사용하십시오
You don't believe me,
put me on a lie detector.
만약 그럴수 있다면..
If I could...
좋아요..
Well...
그럼 절 믿으실 수 있으신가요?
Then you're just gonna
have to trust me.
그런가요 함장님?
Aren't you, sir?
내 잠수함에, CIA의 간첩이 있다네
There's a CIA plant,
a mole, on my sub
나에게 대항해서 말이야
working against me.
누구라도 될 수 있지
It could be anyone.
너도 가능하고
Could be you.
그런데 만약 아니라면
But if it isn't,
증명하게
prove it.
누가 간첩인지 알아오게
Find out who they are.
(Sighs)
좋아 우리가 파내고 나서 그리고?
Okay, so we dig it up,
and then what?
난 끝났어
I'm done.
파키스탄 임무에서 무슨일이 일어났는지
What happened on that mission
in Pakistan,
지금 우리가 밝혀내야 해
we gotta come clean
about it now.
글쎄, 그렇게 말하긴 넌 쉽겠지
Well,
that's easy for you to say.
증거가 될 헬멧기록의 주인이 네가 아니니까
It's not you on that helmet cam
planting evidence.
수백만명을 죽게한 두개의 핵미사일을 이끈
It's not you getting the orders
that led to two nukes
명령을 따른것도 너는 아니잖아
and millions dead.
너는 그들 뒤에 있는 사람이 아니니까
It's not you
they are after, man.
너와 나 둘 다 그들 뒤에 있어
They are after both of us.
그래서 우리가 어떻게 해야되는데 어?
So what are we gonna do
about it, huh?
그냥 입닫고 좋은 선원으로 살다 죽을래?
Just shut up and die
like good sailors?
좋아
All right.
네 방식대로 하자
We'll do this your way.
하지만 이일을 하고 나서
But after we get through this,
난 갈 수있는 한 멀리 도망갈거야
I'm getting as far away
from this as I can.
난 날마다 뭔가 옳은일을 하려고 노력하는데
I'll try to do something right
every day.
그래서 결코 뒤돌아보지 않아
And I'm never looking back.
(Shovel thuds)
(TV playing without audio)
(Footsteps approach) (Exhales)
영업 끝났어
Bar's closed.
크리스틴에 대해 어떤 말이라도?
Any word on Christine?
사진에 나왔던 그 친구 기억해요?
(Exhales) Remember that guy
from the photo?
(Exhales)
그가 거기 있었어요
He was there.
샘
Sam.
아, 아니 그런 게 아니구요
Ah, it-- it wasn't like that.
그가 , 어
He, uh...
(Huffs)
그녀를 구하려다 죽었어요
He got himself killed
protecting her.
당신은 어때요?
How you doing?
내 엉덩일 저쪽으로 차버릴려고 노력중이야
I'm tired of getting
my ass kicked out here.
오 그래요 힘들겠군요
Oh, yeah? How tired?
오늘 일어날 뻔한 전쟁을 당신이 막았어요
You stopped a war
from happening today.
아니야, 난 우리 승조원들의 가족을 죽음으로부터 구하려고 했지
No. I tried to stop them from
killing our crew's family,
크리스틴을 구하려고
from killing Christine.
봐요, 이제 세계적인 플레이어에요
Look,
you're a world player now.
(Sighs)
당신은 당신의 나라를 갖고 있는 거에요
Hell, you're your own country.
17개의 핵미사일과 마이크, 더 필요한게 있나요?
17 nukes and a microphone.
What more do you need?
나 봐요
Me, though?
난 내 아내를 지키지도 못한 그런 놈이라구요
I'm just a guy that
couldn't save his own wife.
이렇게 돌아가는 상황에서 뭘 잡아야 하는 지도 모른다구요
And I'm not cut out for whatever
this whole thing's turning into.
(Sighs)
전 섬을 떠날거에요
I'm leaving the island.
보트가 정박했지만 크리스틴이 없었어요
The family boat docked.
Christine wasn't on it.
그들이 그녈 어디론가 데려갔고, 전 그녈 찾을거에요
They've taken her somewhere,
and I'm gonna find her.
봉쇄를 위해서 콜로라도에 제가 필요하겠지만
I'll need the Colorado
to get me through the blockade,
제가 가는 곳에 절 태워다줄 배가 필요하겠지만
I'll need a boat to take me
to where I'm going,
하지만 전 갈거에요
but I'm going.
그녀가 이곳에 돌아오겠다면, 제가 그녈 데려올거에요
If she's willing to come
back here, I'll bring her,
하지만 전 갈거에요
but I'm going.
좋아.
Okay.
미안해요 그녈 데려오지 못했어요
I'm sorry I couldn't get her.
내 가장 친한 친구에게 부탁한 것 이상으로 해줬어
You did more than I could've
asked my closest friend.
내가 한번 빚졌어
I owe you one.
Yeah.
조금만 빨랐으면 그들을 데려올 수 있었는데
You might be taking that
back in a second.
3일전 당신이 우릴 파키스탄 해변에서
Three days
before you picked us up
태웠을때 우리 팀은 명령을 받고 있었어요
off the coast of Pakistan,
my team was given orders
핵 분석학자를 구출해오라는 명령이었죠
to rescue an exfil
nuclear inspector--
오스카 닐 박사에요
Dr. Oscar Nils.
자 일어나 힘내
(James) Come on. I got you.
(Grunting)
힘내 힘내라고
Come on. (Grunts) Come on.
Let's go.
길..
Gil...
확인했나?
do you copy?
길 우린 탈출한다, 하퍼가 부상당했어
Gil, we're bugging out.
Hopper's hurt.
심각한 부상이야
He's hurt bad.
응급탈출 계획을 실행한다
Enact emergency exfil plan.
하퍼, 정신차려
Hopper! Stay with me.
본부 여긴 탱고 파이브
Hospitality,
this is Tango Five.
우린 랑데뷰 장소에 도착했다
We're at the rendezvous.
Over.
본부 여긴 탱고 파이브 들리는가?
Hospitality, this is tango five.
Do you read?
by 지아아빠 (suhwan.2006@gmail.com)
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com